# **CHRISTOFOROS** RENTIFIS



# **ABOUT ME**

Meticulous web developer with over 2 years of front end experience and passion for responsive website designs and a firm believer in the mobile first approach.

Always focus on latest technologies striving to deliver the most attractive solutions on business requirements. Having experienced multicultural & highly competitive environments, I always try to be invaluable member of my team being equally able to work in both Agile and waterfall approaches resoecting company's values and business objectives.

# **SKILLS**

JavaScript **TypeScript** React HTML5 CSS/SASS/Styled Node JS MongoDB/Mongoose REST API Apollo GraphQL Socket IO MobX/Redux/Context Webpack Gatsby JS Jira Git

## CONTACT

+30 698 700 1819

redifischris@gmail.com

Andromedas 14. Gerakas

/christoforos-rentifis

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **Front End Developer**

Cognity S.A.

Dec 2021 up to present

Develop and maintain the new responsive AVIS leasing portal. Some of my daily activities are:

- · Close collaboration with customer for the finalization of business requirements.
- · Close collaboration with Designers fir UX issues/refinements.
- Team member that translates the business requirements into business user stories.
- · Responsible to apply solution analysis and low level design for all UI components.
- · Responsible for coding, unit-testing and implementing commits, builds and updates for all AVIS UI functionalities.
- · Main Technologies used: ReactJS, CSS.

## **Front End Developer**

Ct 2020 to Dec 2021

Develop and maintain the trading portal of the betting engine backoffice system. Be member of the front clients team, responsible for the new productized feature development of responsive betting web portal from customers around the world. Some of my daily activities are:

- · Apply low level design for the product stories and customization tasks.
- Close collaboration with Ba's for technical obstacles and UX issues/refinements.
- · Coding, unit-testing and implementing commits, builds, and updates in ReactJS components. Maintenance of GIT Repository.
- Apply 3rd level support for production incidents based on contractual SLAs.
- Being part of cross functional teams following agile process (Sprint planning,
- Review, Daily Stands ups, Retrospective etc.

#### Web Developer(freelancer)

Nov 2019 to Dec 2020

Undertake the creation and customazation of commercial and informational responsive websites for various customers

- · Familiarity with CMS (WordPress, WooCommerce & Prestashop).
- · Creating custom widgets using HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript.

#### **MEP Engineer**

Feb 2016 to Sep 2020

Designing and managing the MEP systems of a building. Assisting with decision making, cost estimation, construction administration, documentation, building management and building maintenance.

# **EDUCATION**

**Diploma in Electrical & Computer Enginnering** 

Sep 2008 to Sep 2014

**National Technical University of Athens** 

Major: Communications.

## CERTIFICATION

Front-End Web Development (React) The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

**Tun 2020 to Nov 2020** 

React - The Complete Guide (Hooks, Router, Redux) Udemy

Feb 2020 to Jul 2021

**GraphQL by Example** 

**Jul 2020 to Sep 2021** 

MobX in Depth (Hooks+TypeScript) Udemy

Sep 2020 to Nov 2020

Node.js Express, MongoDB & More Udemy

Jun 2021 to Oct 2021

**Gatsby.js Tutorial and Projects Course** Udemy

**Jul 2021 to Nov 2021** 

# **LANGUAGES**

**Greek:** Native **English: Very Good Russian:** Beginner

# **HOBBIES**













Coffee

S. Media

Sport

Games